They did the unthinkable. They brought it back.
The Relic is a horror, mystery, thriller film directed by Peter Hyams.
A homicide detective teams up with an evolutionary biologist to hunt a
giant creature that is killing people in a Chicago museum.
Dr. Margo Green, played by Penelope Ann Miller.
Lt. Vincent D'Agosta, played by Tom Sizemore.
Dr. Ann Cuthbert, played by Linda Hunt.
Dr. Albert Frock, played by James Whitmore.
Det. Hollingsworth, played by Clayton Rohner.
Dr. Greg Lee, played by Chi Muoi Lo.
The Relic is a 1997 American monster-horror film directed by Peter Hyams and based on
the best-selling 1995 novel Relic by Douglas Preston and Lincoln Child.
The film stars Penelope Ann Miller, Tom Sizemore,
Linda Hunt, and James Whitmore.
In the film, a detective and a biologist try to defeat a South American monstrous reptilian
creature which is on a killing spree in the Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago.
The movie was shot in Chicago at the Field Museum of Natural History.
Production was originally intended to be held at the American
Museum of Natural History in New York City.
However, a deal could not be reached and, after taking interest in the film's
premise, the Field Museum offered to let the studio shoot there instead.
The film was the second on-screen collaboration between Hunt, Miller, and supporting actor
Chi Muoi Lo, all three of whom also worked on the film Kindergarten Cop.
The film was released in the United States on
January 10, 1997, by Paramount Pictures.
It grossed only $48 million worldwide against a $40–60 million budget.
It was the last film appearance of actress Audra Lindley.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, monster, based
on novel or book, museum, amazon rainforest.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.